## **Nithin Oommen George**

Pathanamthitta, India • Tel: + (91) 9497019359 • Email: nithinoommen1997@gmail.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/nithin-oommen-george97

\_\_\_\_\_

Results-oriented Cybersecurity specialist having experience teaching cybersecurity and working as a SOC Analyst. Currently working as a College Lecturer, presenting entertaining lectures on cybersecurity subjects and supporting curriculum development. During an internship, I gained experience monitoring and responding to security issues. I also have good technical capabilities in network security, penetration testing, and numerous security tools.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2024 – Present *Cybersecurity Facilitator* Atmic Systemics Kozhikode (India)

### 2022 – 2024 College Lecture Viswabrahmana College Pathanamthitta (India)

- Delivered lecture on cybersecurity, network security, and cyber forensics.
- Guided students through practical sessions and projects.
- Developed course materials and assessment tools.
- Assisted in curriculum development for cybersecurity courses.

# 7/2022– 10/2022 SOC Analyst Intern Cibera Defence Private Limited Trivandrum (India)

- DelMonitored, detected, and responded to security incidents.
- Analyzed Network operations and Linux environments.
- Conducted Event ID analysis and reported findings.
- Gained Experience with SIEM tools and platforms like LetsDefend, TryHackMe.

### RELEVANT SKILLS

- Computer skills: Microsoft Office, Networking, Cybersecurity, SOC Analyst, Penetration Testing, Python Programming
- Tools: Nmap, Wireshark, Nikto, Nessus, Metasploit...
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

Professional/Social: Teamwork, Project- Management, Communication, Leadership,

Organization, Problem-solving

• Languages: Native Language, English

#### EDUCATION

# 2022 *M.Sc in Cyber Forensics* Mahatma Gandhi University India)

(Pathanamthitta,

- Computer Organization Fundamentals
- Cybersecurity Techniques
- Programming for Security
- Advanced Networking and IoT
- Risk Assessment and Legal Aspects

# 2020 *B.Sc in Cyber Forensics* Mahatma Gandhi University India)

(Pathanamthitta,

- Linux Fundamentals
- Cybersecurity Techniques
- Programming for Security
- Networking
- Hacking Concepts

# 2017 *DME* Vethamonikam Memorial CSI Polytechnic College (Marthandam,India)

- Proficient in 2D/3D CAD Software: AutoCAD
- Strong understanding of thermodynamics, fluid mechanics, and heat transfer.
- Knowledge of manufacturing processes: CNC machining, welding, casting

### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

2024 – Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH) EC-Council

2023 – Certified Penetration Testing (CPT) REDTEAM HACKER ACADEMY

2021 – Ethical Hacking Associate (EHA) EC-Council

2018 – C&C++ ECIT

2017 – WEB DESIGNING ECIT